♪From primal chaos to the starry sky♪
♪In the whole world, we hold balance♪
♪The cauldron tempers divine blades♪
♪The furnace refines the empty void♪
♪The Way is in mystic fate♪
♪Dare to part the primal cosmos♪
[Pull Strings]
[Adapted from the novel
by Yan Gui Zheng Zhuan]
[Episode 29]
Do you remember
sitting by our pond?
We caught a little fish
and made a big pot of fish soup.
Do you ever recall
those few missing sheep
that ate flowers but no grass?
And also,
your Junior Ling'e,
who didn't eat much
but was always chubby and mischievous?
Changshou,
all these years,
so much has happened over the years,
and so many people have
been by your side.
You were never alone.
[Scripture of Steadiness]
The Scripture of Steadiness?
Senior, I've copied 500 times.
Please check it.
Junior.
The Demon Emperor has returned.
You should have run.
Instead, you rushed in.
Senior, you're not playing it safe.
Punish yourself with 500 copies.
Where are you going?
Actually,
coming to Jade Division,
meeting you,
Mentor,
and everyone...
I'm really happy.
Thought I had no family anymore,
but now,
I will fight for my family.
Senior.
I'm sorry.
I may never copy scriptures again.
Junior.
Changshou.
Your foundation is too weak.
You'd better stay out of this.
Senior Changshou, go.
We'll hold off the Demon Emperor.
Don't go. You'll die.
So what?
Mentor already died in battle.
The other disciples are dead too.
You've always looked after me, Senior.
This time, I'll fight for you.
So it was you.
Your Highness.
Thank you.
You helped me come this far.
Today, we may live or die.
If we both survive,
will you take me as your disciple?
I...
I understand.
A war is upon us. Stay focused.
Let's talk later.
I'm back again.
Why shoulder everything?
No matter how huge it is?
And somehow,
you've got all these people
following you into this mess.
Your foundation is damaged, old man.
What are you even doing here?
What am I doing?
I want to go back too.
But I cannot.
Water Dragon Spouts lined up in queue.
But this place is way too dangerous.
Dangerous?
I'm not the coward you think I am.
I just wanna stay and see.
See that?
I've always had a feeling
that my disciple was meant
for great things.
Clearly,
you can set up formations like that,
and
your Evasion Art is formidable.
Yet you hide in Jade Division.
Mentor, I actually...
Do not say it.
I'm afraid I couldn't handle it.
Changshou.
I haven't done much
with my life.
But,
meeting you,
taking you in,
teaching you...
I think I did pretty well.
Changshou.
Remember this.
From now on,
do whatever you need to do.
Just remember one thing.
Tell me, Mentor.
Go raise some hell!
Turn the whole world upside down.
Show them what Jade Division's made of.
Yes, Mentor.
♪I know the world's full of deceit♪
Turn the world upside down!
Fight through hell and back!
Make heaven and hell tremble!
Give 'em something to fear!
We'll shake the skies!
We're unstoppable!
Maybe I got
a little carried away there.
Changshou.
Maybe I talked a little too big.
Could you raise just a little less hell?
Wait, Chang...
Why show me all this?
Don't you get it yet?
I already found a way out.
You found it?
♪Who's clamoring behind♪
Heaven derives forty-nine paths,
yet one escapes.
All karma
had its answer from the start.
I was too foolish
to see this until now.
Thank you, Jin Chan.
Were it not for you
giving me these 3,600 years,
I'd never find enlightenment.
♪Battling fierce demons♪
But what you showed me
all pointed to failure.
Of course you couldn't see it.
Because this is Fate's game.
♪Rising with golden armor♪
Everyone around you is karma.
Only by remembering them all
can you find the way out.
But you
forgot them all long ago.
Impossible.
I've lived through four lives
for over thirty thousand years.
Even I never grasped it.
How could you...
Shut up, you fool.
You're nothing but Fate's castoff.
Quit trying to make yourself relevant.
Let me tell you something.
From the very beginning,
Fate never once cared about you.
Now, I'll show you
what it means to be the Chosen One.
Fate.
I've seen through your secrets.
I know everything now.
If you want them to stay secret,
come face me!
Impossible.
Impossible!
Jin Chan,
if in the next life,
you and I meet again,
I'll surely kill you with my own hands.
Take me.
Take me to see Fate.
I said it already.
From the very beginning,
Fate never once cared about you.
Not even once.
No way.
Take me!
Fate!
I am the Chosen One.
I've done so much for you.
Why treat me like this, Fate?
I waited for you for 30,000 years.
[Great Tribulation]
Before the Demon Emperor,
you stay so calm?
I have words
to say to Fairy Yunxiao.
Fairy Yunxiao no longer exists.
I have words
to say to Fairy Yunxiao.
Don't you fear death?
You may not believe me.
But I've seen more death
than you have.
In that case,
whatever you have to say, go ahead.
I'll allow you to finish.
I want to say
about what you asked me before...
I thought it through.
I would.
I would
stay by your side forever,
never to part.
♪An unexpected meeting
in this Primordial World♪
If you become an immortal,
I shall become an immortal.
If you evade afar,
I shall evade afar too.
This is an amulet.
In the Mortal Realm,
there's one magic that never dies.
It's called sincerity.
Now that we both have it,
I'd say our hearts are in sync.
Wherever you go,
I'll go too.
No reasons needed,
and no deception at all.
Trust me.
I won't
let go of your hand.
♪Day after day, with whom to share♪
♪Never walked the road
of joy and sorrow♪
♪No better than a mortal♪
Don't you resent me for using you?
Aren't you afraid I'll trick you?
After being with you these days,
I trust you.
♪How to walk this different path
with you♪
Little brat!
♪At storm's end,
stars gleam, and clouds drift♪
♪Together we smile,
watching moonrise and sunset♪
I want to stay with you,
be by your side from now on.
Would you?
I would give up all
I have sought for over thirty years
♪Earthbound, yet I touch the sky♪
to bring you back.
♪In my heart,
mortal lights entwine the clouds♪
Are you done?
There is more.
This time,
I might not make it after all.
♪Someone has unsettled your heart♪
I'm sorry.
♪An edge hides, yet flows with ease♪
♪Making me lean down and confirm slowly♪
♪Not knowing what love truly is♪
♪Just as it was at first♪
♪Day after day, with whom to share♪
♪Never walked the road
of joy and sorrow♪
Yunxiao.
♪Not knowing love's depth♪
♪Who truly cares♪
♪How to walk this different path
with you♪
♪At storm's end,
stars gleam, and clouds drift♪
♪Together we smile,
watching moonrise and sunset♪
Li Changshou.
I bow again to Lord Fate.
After 3,600 years,
I see it all clearly now.
And
what do you see?
Before,
you brought me
into this Primordial World,
informing me of the Great Tribulation.
It planted a seed in my heart.
Over these years,
everything I've been through,
every scheme and struggle,
made it take root
and grow into a towering tree.
All things in this world are karma.
I went to Bear Island.
The Pregenesis Sword emerged.
I aided Ao Yi.
It triggered the Dragon Palace chaos.
It seemed I was avoiding disaster.
But all along,
I was bringing it about.
I am its very cause.
All living things
have a Fated Mandate.
Yes.
The Fated Mandate.
Fate's decree.
♪Once a drifting weed, I loved to roam♪
In Fairy Yunxiao's heart,
you planted a lust for treasure.
In mine,
you planted the urge to hide.
In Jin Chan's heart,
you planted a wish to end all.
♪Silent in subtleties♪
The first step of all this karma
♪Though millions block, it echoes loud♪
was all you.
Fate.
That is all?
♪Plain and unremarkable♪
Of course.
If that were all,
I'd be no better than Jin Chan.
Why would you come to see me?
I'm here to end all of this.
And the key
is this thing.
♪My soul is standing like a mountain♪
Right?
♪Chaos births a flowing ode♪
Every cycle this sundial turns
represents one Great Tribulation.
What if
♪The furnace refines my pure heart♪
there were no sundial
created by Fate at all?
♪With firm resolve, I roam the sky♪
♪Under crushing weight♪
♪Wings lift toward clear skies♪
A mere mortal,
daring to defy Fate?
♪Old scars reveal the truth♪
How do I know without trying?
♪Close eyes to sense the world♪
♪Years splash ink♪
With your cultivation,
trying 100 more times is still futile.
Fate,
I still have plenty of time.
I will spend every last minute
striking it without pause.
This time, you lost.
♪Drums and gongs split the air♪
♪Veins blaze hotter than fire♪
♪A mere yet fearless mortal♪
♪So-called karma♪
♪I temper a clear conscience♪
♪A wanderer turned to ash and bone♪
♪Still, I live this life standing tall♪
Why seek your own ruin?
With your strength alone,
how can you stop the Great Tribulation?
Even if I'm nothing against it,
I'll die trying anyway.
♪Years splash ink♪
Fate.
You are truly powerful.
May I speak to someone dear
for a few final words?
Fine.
Li Changshou.
I grant you a proper end.
Thank you.
♪Veins blaze hotter than fire♪
♪A mere yet fearless mortal♪
[Matter]
Junior.
Senior?
Senior, where are you?
I used a swap talisman
to bind you to this paper butterfly.
With Fate's aid,
every lightning that struck me
boosted spiritual power on it
even further.
Right now, I can finally get you
into the Cloud Illusion.
Senior, I'll come find you now.
Wait for me.
Ling'e.
Mentor.
Where are you going?
Senior is looking for me.
Take me with you.
Mentor.
Take me. I want to see him.
Senior.
Changshou.
Are you okay?
Why are you here?
I didn't want to come.
Just...
Ling'e dragged me here.
It's...
That's right.
We all want to stay by your side.
Since you're all here...
Mentor.
I used to boss you around
and scold you.
I even called you an old fool.
I never took you to these things.
I never let you feel
what it means to be a Mentor.
But if you hadn't said,
"Go raise some hell,
no matter what,"
I never would've seen it.
Thank you for your final lesson.
Let me call you "old fool"
one last time.
You brat.
Old fool.
Changshou.
You know what I was just thinking?
I recalled when we first met.
You were hidden in the grass,
barely breathing,
wretched and worn.
I was herding sheep.
Those two sheep in the painting.
Baa, baa.
They suddenly stopped grazing
and found you there.
I had always lived alone.
When I met you, I thought,
I must keep him safe for life.
But you were so meticulous,
playing it safe in everything,
always protecting all of us.
Even heaven
has its limits,
but there's always a way out.
All that matters
is that we're together
as a family.
So no matter what lies ahead,
we'll shoulder it with you together.
I'll heed your words, Mentor.
Good boy.
Thank you.
Junior.
As for your Senior...
I'm sly
and self-serving.
I always use you as a shield.
Taking you in back then
was also a way to use you.
That Chaos Bell at your neck
can reverse time and space
in all realms.
I could use it
to calculate the Great Tribulation.
Everything I did
was for that purpose.
Teaching you Evasion Arts,
passing you Scripture of Steadiness,
and taking care of you
was all for that purpose.
To me,
you're a counting rod.
A rare one.
And if it's missing,
I'd be very distressed.
Senior.
I know you often say
everyone in your eyes
is but a tool.
Only then
can you avoid karma and live in peace.
But I know,
if you were truly like that,
you wouldn't get into this situation
for our sakes.
I'm not stupid.
Calculating every scheme
is just your cover.
You once faced danger for us.
This time,
let us do something for you.
Looks like my Junior has grown.
In that case,
Junior,
please hear the question.
This Chaos Bell has power
to reverse time and space in all realms.
Against the lightning up ahead,
to break that sundial,
I must use this Chaos Bell's power
to stop and rewind time.
That's my only way out.
So tell me,
what should I do
to smash that sundial?
But you forgot,
you cannot use the Chaos Bell's power.
Of course I know I can't.
A treasure like this
is only for Lan Ling'e.
If you destroy the sundial,
all order in Primordial World falls.
That too is a Great Tribulation.
And you
will also perish, body and soul.
In that case,
I will become the sundial,
guarding the order of all things
in the Primordial World.
As long as I stand,
the Great Tribulation won't come.
I believe in you, Senior.
Not a chance.
♪From primal chaos to the starry sky♪
♪In the whole world,
we shall hold the balance♪
♪The cauldron tempers divine blades♪
♪The furnace refines the empty void♪
♪The Way is in mystic fate♪
♪Be brave enough
to split the primal chaos wide open♪
Junior.
Mentor.
Take care.
No one will appreciate it.
No one will even remember you.
Every trace of your existence
in the Primordial World
will disappear.
Knowing that, are you still willing?
It is just as I wish.
♪I know the world's full of deceit♪
[Steady]
Mentor.
I know you don't like drumsticks.
Junior, I still have half down here.
I'll save it for you.
[Steady]
♪Caught in karma, stained by dust♪
♪Carefree, they say♪
♪Still I chase creation's secret♪
The sword is
where the heart is.
I get it.
You do?
This is just a trinket
I made in my spare time.
It is called Sensing Stone.
I'm very strong.
♪Who's clamoring behind♪
♪Acting like fierce demons♪
♪I steadily divine the world's fate♪
[Steady]
Farewell,
everyone.
♪And set formations in the world♪
♪I will go in and stir things up♪
[Steady]
[500 Years Later]
♪Chaos broke; the ancient beasts fell♪
♪Millions of years flew by♪
♪No immortal terrace in sight♪
♪Only the songs of immortals are heard♪
[Jade Division]
Ling'e.
Mentor.
Let me handle these chores.
Go and rest.
You're a young lady.
How can you do such rough work?
If only you had a Senior.
He could handle the heavy chores,
and neither of us would have to.
But if a capable Senior really existed,
could you even keep him under control?
That's true.
Just always feeling like
we forgot something.
What is it?
Mentor,
do you remember centuries ago,
how I came to Jade Division?
You...
You were...
That was centuries ago.
Mentor can't remember.
Minister.
Your Majesty.
Send this invitation
to the Ascendance Sect.
This is...
My invitation,
inviting human cultivators over
to make a judgment.
They're fighting again?
It's the affair of the East Sea.
Why do you get the say?
I am Dragon King's Senior.
Of course I get the say.
You...
Unreasonable.
Watch my sword.
None of your business.
Shh.
I, Bian Zhuang, fought for bonds.
And I have no regrets.
Le'er's matters
are my concern.
Shut up.
I won't.
You...
Told you to shut up.
But you won't.
You talk too much.
You went to the Dragon Palace again?
I did.
Honestly.
It's been centuries.
You go to the Dragon Palace every year.
What are you after?
Looking for a star.
A star?
Stars are in the sky.
All the other stars are up there.
But the star I'm after
fell into the sea.
Good line.
That's a good line.
All the other stars
are up there.
But the star...
As dignified Celestial Emperor,
you should be in the Celestial Court,
so why come to Bear Island?
In these times,
the realm is at peace.
No trouble for over 500 years.
Isn't it all the same where I am?
Yes.
It's been 500 years.
Over these 500 years,
don't you feel we forgot something?
For instance,
how did we first meet?
why are we dressed like this?
And also,
do you not feel
someone is missing on Bear Island?
I seem
to have the same feeling.
We have lived for ages.
Forgetting a few things
is only natural.
I researched it.
Our emotions
have a defense mechanism.
Things we don't wanna recall
get automatically forgotten.
The sword is
where the heart is.
Who was it
that told me this?
Smells familiar.
[Hall of United Spirits]
Mentor.
♪See mortal joys and sorrows♪
♪Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds♪
♪Alas, love has many twists and turns♪
♪Memories filled with sorrow♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪
♪Down a few more cups of wine♪
♪Through land and sea,
I ask you to come♪
♪For honor's sake, upright and grand♪
♪Alas, our story is short♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪